Flies. Chapter 8, Gift for the Darkness.
Piggy looked up miserably from the dawn pale beach to the dark mountain. Are you
sure? Really sure? I mean, I told you a dozen times now, said Ralph. We saw it.
Do you think we're safe down here? How the hell should I know? Ralph jerked
away from him and walked a few paces along the beach. Jack was kneeling and
drawing a circular pattern in the sand with his forefinger. Piggy's voice came
to them, hushed. "Are you sure? Really?"
"Go up and see," said Jack contemptuously. "And good riddance." "No
fear." "The beast had teeth," said Ralph and big black eyes. He shuddered
violently. Piggy took off his one round of glass and polished the surface. "What
we going to do?" Ralph turned toward the platform. The conch glimmered among the
trees, a white blob against the place where the sun would rise. He pushed back
his mop. I don't know. He remembered the panic flight down the mountainside. I
don't think we'd ever fight a thing that size, honestly. You know, we'd talk, but
we wouldn't fight a tiger. We'd hide.
Even Jack could hide. Jack still looked at the sand. What about my hunters?
Simon came stealing out of the shadows by the shelters. Ralph ignored Jack's
question. He pointed to the touch of yellow above the sea. As long as there's
light, we're brave enough. But then, and now that thing squats by the fire, as
though it didn't want us to be rescued, he was twisting his hands now
unconsciously. His voice rose. So, we can't have a signal fire. We're beaten.
A point of gold appeared above the sea, and at once all the sky lightened. What
about my hunters? Boys armed with sticks. Jack got to his feet. His face
was red as he marched away. Piggy put on his one glass and looked at Ralph. Now
you've done it. You've been rude about his hunters. Oh, shut up. The sound of
the inexpertly blown cunch interrupted them as though he were serenating the
rising sun. Jack went on blowing till the shelters were a stir, and the
hunters crept to the platform, and the little onins whimpered, as now they so
frequently did. Ralph rose obediently and Piggy and they went to the platform.
Talk, said Ralph bitterly. Talk, talk, talk. He took the conch from Jack. This
meeting, Jack interrupted him. I called it. If you hadn't called it, I should
have. You just blew the conch. Well, isn't that calling it? Oh, take it. Go
on, talk. Ralph thrust the conch into Jack's arms and sat down on the trunk.
I've called an assembly, said Jack.
Because of a lot of things first, you know, now we've seen the beast. We
crawled up. We were only a few feet away. The beast sat up and looked at us.
I don't know what it does. We don't even know what it is. The beast comes out of
the sea, out of the dark trees. Quiet, shouted Jack. You listen. The beast is
sitting up there. Whatever it is, perhaps it's waiting. Hunting. Yes,
hunting. Hunting, said Jack. He remembered his age-old tremors in the
forest. Yes, the beast is a hunter. Only Shut up. The next thing is that we
couldn't kill it. And the next is that Ralph said, "My hunters are no good." I
never said that. I've got the cunch.
Ralph thinks you're cowards running away from the boar and the beast. And that's
not all. There was a kind of sigh on the platform as if everyone knew what was
coming. Jack's voice went up. Tremulus get determined, pushing against the
uncooperative silence. He's like Piggy.
He says things like Piggy. He isn't a proper chief. Jack clutched the cunch to
him. He's a coward himself. For a moment, he paused and then went on. On
top, when Roger and me went on, he stayed back. I went, too. After? The two
boys glared at each other through screens of hair. I went on too, said
Ralph. Then I ran away. So did you. Call me a coward then. Jack turned to the
hunters. He's not a hunter. He'd never have got us meat. He isn't a prefect and
we don't know anything about him. He just gives orders and expects people to
obey for nothing. All this talk. All this talk, shouted Ralph. Talk. Who
wanted it? Who called the meeting? Ralph turned red in the face, his chin sunk
back. He glowered up under his eyebrows.
All right then, he said in tones of deep meaning and menace. All right. He held
the conch against his chest with one hand and stabbed the air with his index
finger. Who thinks Ralph oughtn't to be chief? He looked expectantly at the boys
ranged round who had frozen. Under the palms there was deadly silence. "Hands
up," said Jack strongly. "Whoever wants Ralph not to be chief." The silence
continued, breathless and heavy and full of shame. Slowly the red drained from
Jack's cheeks, then came back with a painful rush. He licked his lips and
turned his head at an angle so that his gaze avoided the embarrassment of
linking with another's eye. "How many think?" His voice trailed off. The hands
that held the conch shook. He cleared his throat and spoke loudly. "All right,
then." He laid the conch with great care in the grass at his feet. The
humiliating tears were running from the corner of each eye. "I'm not going to
play any longer. Not with you." Most of the boys were looking down now with the
grass or their feet. Jack cleared his throat again. "I'm not going to be a
part of Ralph's lot." He looked along the right-hand logs, numbering the
hunters that had been acquired. "I'm going off by myself. He can catch his
own pigs. Anyone who wants to hunt when I do can come too. He blundered out of
the triangle toward the drop to the white sand. Jack. Jack turned and looked
at back at Ralph. For a moment he paused and then cried out high-pitched,
enraged. No. He leapt down from the platform and ran along the beach, paying
no heed to the steady fall of his tears.
And until he dived into the forest, Ralph watched him. Piggy was indignant.
I've been talking, Ralph, and you just stood there like softly looking at Piggy
and not seeing him. Ralph spoke to himself. He'll come back. When the sun
goes down, he'll come. He looked at the cons piggy's hand. What? Well, there.
Piggy gave up the attempt to rebuke Ralph. He polished his glass again and
went back to his subject. We can do without Jack Meridu. There's others
besides him on this island. But now we really got a beast, though. I can't
hardly believe it. We'll need to stay close to the platform. There'll be less
need of him and his hunting. So now we can really decide on what's what.
There's no help, Piggy. Nothing to be done. For a while they sat in depressed
silence. Then Simon stood up and took the cunch from Piggy, who was so
astonished that he remained on his feet.
Ralph looked up at Simon. Simon, what is it this time? A half sound of jeering
ran round the circle, and Simon shrank from it. I thought there might be
something to do, something we again. The pressure of the assembly took his voice
away. He sought for help and sympathy and chose Piggy. He turned half toward
him, clutching the conch to his brown chest. I think we ought to climb the
mountain. The circle shivered with dread. Simon broke off and turned to
Piggy, who was looking at him with an expression of derisive incomprehension.
What's the good of climbing up to this here beast when Ralph and the other two
couldn't do nothing? Simon whispered his answer. What else is there to do? His
speech made, he allowed Piggy to lift the conch out of his hands. Then he
retired and sat as far away from the others as possible. Piggy was speaking
now with more assurance, and with what, if the circumstances had not been so
serious, the others would have recognized his pleasure. I said we could
all do without a certain person. Now I say we got to decide on what can be
done. And I think I could tell you what Ralph's going to say next. The most
important thing on the island is the smoke. And you can't have no smoke
without a fire. Ralph made a restless movement. No go, Piggy. We've got no
fire. That thing sits up there. We'll have to stay here. Piggy lifted the
conscious though to add power to his next words. We got no fire on the
mountain. But what's wrong with a fire down here? A fire could be built on them
rocks, on the sand even. We'd make smoke just the same. That's right. smoke by
the bathing pool. The boys began to babble. Only Piggy could have the
intellectual daring to suggest moving the fire from the mountain. So, we'll
have the fire down here, said Ralph. He looked about him. We can build it just
here between the bathing pool and the platform. Of course, he broke off,
frowning, thinking the thing out, unconsciously, tugging at the stub of a
nail with his teeth. Of course, the smoke won't show so much, not be seen so
far away. But we needn't go near the others nodded in perfect comprehension.
There would be no need to go near. We'll build the fire now. The greatest ideas
are the simplest. Now there was something to be done. They worked with
passion. Piggy was so full of delight in expanding liberty and Jack's departure,
so full of pride in his contribution to the good of society that he helped to
fetch wood. The wood he fetched was close at hand, a fallen tree on the
platform that they did not need for the assembly. Yet to the others, the
sanctity of the platform had protected even what was useless there. Then the
twins realized they would have a fire near them as a comfort in the night. And
this set a few littleins dancing and clapping hands. The wood was not so dry
as the fuel they had used on the mountain. Much of it was damply rotten
and full of insects that scured. Logs had to be lifted from the soil with
care, or they crumbled into soden powder. More than this, in order to
avoid going deep into the forest, the boys worked near at hand on any fallen
wood, no matter how tangled with new growth. The skirts of the forest and the
scar were familiar, near the conch and the shelters, and sufficiently friendly
in daylight. What they might become in darkness, nobody cared to think. They
worked therefore with great energy and cheerfulness, though as time crept by
there was a suggestion of panic in the energy and hysteria in the cheerfulness.
They built a pyramid of leaves and twigs, branches and logs on the bare
sand by the platform. For the first time on the island, Piggy himself removed his
one glass, knelt down, and focused the sun on tinder. Soon there was a ceiling
of smoke and a bush of yellow flame. The little who had seen few fires
since the first catastrophe became wildly excited. They danced and sang,
and there was a partyish air about the gathering. At last, Ralph stopped work
and stood up, smudging the sweat from his face with a dirty forearm. We'll
have to have a small fire. This one's too big to keep up. Piggy sat down
carefully on the sand and began to polish his glass. We could experiment.
We could find out how to make a small hot fire and then put green branches on
to make smoke. Some of them leaves must be better for that than the others. As
the fire died down, so did the excitement. The little stopped singing
and dancing and drifted away toward the sea or the fruit trees or the shelters.
Ralph dropped down in the sand.
Well have to make a new list of who's to look after the fire. If you can
find him," he looked round. Then, for the first time, he saw how few biggin
there were, and understood why the work had been so hard. "Where's Maurice?"
Piggy wiped his glass again. "I expect."
"No, he wouldn't go into the forest by himself, would he?" Ralph jumped up, ran
swiftly around the fire, and stood by Piggy, holding up his hair. "But we've
got to have a list. There's you and me and Sam and Eric, and he would not look
at Piggy, but spoke casually." "Where's Bill and Roger?" Piggy leaned forward
and put a fragment of wood on the fire.
"I expect they've gone. I expect they won't play neither. Ralph sat down and
began to poke little holes in the sand.
He was surprised to see that one had a drop of blood by it. He examined his
bitten nail closely and watched the little globe of blood that gathered
where the quick was not away. Piggy went on speaking. I seen them stealing off
when he was gathering wood. They went that way the same way as he went
himself. Ralph finished his inspection and looked up into the air. The sky, as
if in sympathy with the great changes among them, was different today, and so
misty that in some places the hot air seemed white. The disc of the sun was
dull silver, as though it were nearer and not so hot. Yet the air stifled.
They always been making trouble, haven't they? The voice came near his shoulder
and sounded anxious. We can do without them. Well be happier now, won't
we? Ralph sat. The twins came, dragging a great log and grinning in their
triumph. They dumped the log among the embers so that sparks flew. We can do
all right on our own, can't we? For a long time, while the log dried, caught
fire, and turned red hot, Ralph sat in the sand, and said nothing. He did not
see Piggy go to the twins and whisper to them, nor how the three boys went
together into the forest. Here you are, he came to himself with a jolt. Piggy
and the other two were by him. They were laden with fruit. I thought perhaps,
said Piggy, we ought to have a feast kind of. The three boys sat down. They
had a great mass of the fruit with them, and all of it properly ripe. They
grinned at Ralph as he took some and began to eat. Thanks, he said. Then,
with an accent of pleased surprise.
Thanks. Do all right on our own, said Piggy. It's them that haven't no common
sense that make trouble on this island.
We'll make a little hot fire. Ralph remembered what had been worrying him.
Where's Simon? I don't know. You don't think he's climbing the mountain? Piggy
broke into noisy laughter and took more fruit. He might be, he gulped his mouthful. He's
cracked. Simon had passed through the area of fruit trees. But today the
little have been too busy with the fire on the beach, and they had not pursued
him there. He went on among the creepers until he reached the great mat that was
woven by the open space and crawled inside. Beyond the screen of leaves, the
sunlight pelted down, and the butterflies danced in the middle of
their unending dance. He knelt down, and the arrow of the sun fell on him. That
other time the air had seemed to vibrate with heat, but now it threatened. Soon
the sweat was running from his long coarse hair. He shifted restlessly, but
there was no avoiding the sun. Presently he was thirsty, and then very thirsty.
He continued to sit. Far off along the beach, Jack was standing before a small group of boys.
He was looking brilliantly happy.
Hunting, he said. He sized them up. Each of them wore the remains of a black cap
and ages ago they had stood in two demure rows and their voices had been
the song of angels. We'll hunt. I'm going to be chief. They nodded and the
crisis passed easily. And then about the beast. They moved, looked at the forest.
I say this, we aren't going to bother about the beast. He nodded at them.
We're going to forget the beast. That's right. Yes, forget the beast. If Jack
was astonished by their fervor, he did not show it. And another thing, we shan
dream so much down here. This is near the end of the island. They agreed
passionately out of the depths of their tormented private lives. Now listen, we
might go later to the castle rock, but now I'm going to get more of the biggin
away from the K and all that. We'll kill a pig and give a feast. He paused and
went on more slowly. And about the beast. When we kill, we'll leave some of
the kill for it. Then it won't bother us, maybe. He stood up abruptly. We'll
go into the forest now and hunt. He turned and trotted away, and after a
moment they followed him obediently.
They spread out nervously in the forest.
Almost at once, Jack found the dung and scattered roots that told of pig, and
soon the track was fresh. Jack signaled the rest of the hunt to be quiet and
went forward by himself. He was happy and wore the damp darkness of the forest
like his old clothes. He crept down a slope to rocks and scattered trees by
the sea. The pigs lay, bloated bags of fat, sensuously enjoying the shadows
under the trees. There was no wind, and they were unsuspicious, and practice had
made Jack silent as the shadows. He stole away again, and instructed his
hidden hunters. Presently they all began to inch forward, sweating in the silence
and heat. Under the trees, an ear flapped idally. A little apart from the rest,
sunk in deep maternal bliss, lay the largest sow of the lot. She was black
and pink, and the great bladder of her belly was fringed with a row of piglets
that slept or burrowed and squeaked. 15 yards from the drove, Jack stopped, and
his arm, straightening, pointed at the sow. He looked round in inquiry to make
sure that everyone understood, and the other boys nodded at him. The row of
right arms slid back. Now the drove of pigs started up and at a range of only
10 yards the wooden spears with fire hardened points flew toward the chosen
pig. One piglet with a demented shriek rushed into the sea trailing Roger's
spear behind it. The SA gave a gasping squeal and staggered up with two spears
sticking in her fat flank. The boys shouted and rushed forward. The piglets
scattered and the SA burst the advancing line and went crashing away through the
forest. After her, they raced along the pig track, but the forest was too dark
and tangled so that Jack, cursing, stopped them and cast among the trees.
Then he said nothing for a time, but breathed fiercely so that they were awed
by him and looked at each other in uneasy admiration. Presently he stabbed
down at the ground with his finger.
There. Before the others could examine the drop of blood, Jack had swerved off,
judging a trace, touching a bow that gave, so he followed, mysteriously right
and assured, and the hunters trod behind him. He stopped before a covert in
there. They surrounded the covert, but the SA got away with the sting of
another spear in her flank. The trailing butts hindered her, and the sharp
crosscut points were a torment. She blundered into a tree, forcing a spear
still deeper, and after that any of the hunters could follow her easily by the
drops of vivid blood. The afternoon wore on, hazy and dreadful with damp heat.
The SA staggered her way ahead of them, bleeding and mad, and the hunters
followed, wedded to her in lust, excited by the long chase and the dropped blood.
They could see her now, nearly got up with her, but she spurted with her last
strength, and held ahead of them again.
They were just behind her when she staggered into an open space where
bright flowers grew and butterflies danced around each other and the air was
hot and still here. Struck down by the heat, the SA fell and the hunters hurled
themselves at her. This dreadful eruption from an unknown world made her
frantic. She squealled and bucked and the air was full of sweat and noise and
blood and terror. Roger ran round the heap, proddding with his spear wherever
pig flesh appeared. Jack was on top of the sow, stabbing downward with his
knife. Roger found a lodgement for his point and began to push till he was
leaning with his whole weight. The spear moved forward inch by inch, and the
terrified squealing became a high-pitched scream. Then Jack found the
throat, and the hot blood spouted over his hands. The sow collapsed under them,
and they were heavy and fulfilled upon her. The butterflies still danced,
preoccupied in the center of the clearing. At last, the immediacy of the
kill subsided. The boys drew back, and Jack stood up, holding out his hands.
"Look!" He giggled and flicked them while the boys laughed at his wreaking
palms. Then Jack grabbed Morris and rubbed the stuff over his cheeks. Roger
began to withdraw his spear and boys noticed it for the first time. Robert
stabilized the thing in a phrase which was received aoriously. Ride up her ass.
Did you hear? Did you hear what he said?
Ride up her ass. This time Robert and Maurice acted the parts, and Maurice's
acting of the pig's efforts to avoid the advancing spear was so funny that the
boys cried with laughter. At length, even this palled Jack began to clean his
bloody hands on the rock. Then he started work on the SA and ponched her,
lugging out the hot bags of colored guts, pushing them into a pile on the
rock while the others watched him. He talked as he worked. We'll take the meat
along the beach. I'll go back to the platform and invite them to a feast.
That should give us time. Roger spoke.
Chief, uh, how can we make a fire? Jack squatted back and frowned at the pig.
We'll raid them and take fire. There must be four of you, Henry and you,
Robert and Maurice. We'll put on paint and sneak up. Roger can snatch a branch
while I say what I want. The rest of you can get this back to where we were.
We'll build the fire there. And after that, he paused and stood up, looking at
the shadows under the trees. His voice was lower when he spoke again, but we'll
leave part of the kill for He knelt down again and was busy with his knife. The
boys crowded around him. He spoke over his shoulder to Roger. Sharpen a stick
at both ends. Presently he stood up, holding the dripping SA's head in his
hands. Where's that stick here? Ram one end in the earth. Oh, it's rock. Jam it
in that crack there. Jack held up the head and jammed the soft throat down on
the pointed end of the stick which pierced through into the mouth. He stood
back and the head hung there, a little blood dribbling down the stick.
Instinctively the boys drew back too, and the forest was very still. They
listened, and the loudest noise was the buzzing of flies over the spilled guts.
Jack spoke in a whisper, "Pick up the pig!" Maurice and Robert skewered the
carcass, lifted the dead weight, and stood ready. In the silence, and
standing over the dry blood, they looked suddenly fertive. Jack spoke loudly.
"This head is for the beast. It's a gift." The silence accepted the gift and
aed them. The head remained there, dim-eyed, grinning faintly, blood
blackening between the teeth. All at once they were running away as fast as
they could through the forest where the open beach. Simon stayed where he was, a
small brown image concealed by the leaves. Even if he shut his eyes, the
SA's head still remained like an after image. The half-shot eyes were dim with
the infinite cynicism of adult life.
They assured Simon that everything was a bad business. I know that. Simon discovered
that he had spoken aloud. He opened his eyes quickly, and there was the head,
grinning amusedly in the strange daylight, ignoring the flies, the
spilled guts, even ignoring the indignity of being spiked on a stick. He
looked away, licking his dry lips. A gift for the beast. Might not the beast
come for it? The head, he thought appeared to agree with him. "Run away,"
said the head silently. "Go back to the others. It was a joke, really. Why
should you bother? You were just wrong, that's all. A little headache. Something
you ate, perhaps." "Go back, child," said the head silently. Simon looked up,
feeling the weight of his wet hair, and gazed at the sky. Up there, for once,
were clouds, great bulging towers that sprouted away over the island, gray and
cream and copper colored. The clouds were sitting on the land. They squeezed,
produced moment by moment this close, tormenting heat. Even the butterflies
deserted the open space where the obscene thing grinned and dripped. Simon
lowered his head, carefully keeping his eyes shut, then sheltered them with his
hand. There were no shadows under the trees, but everywhere a pearly
stillness, so that what was real seemed elusive and without definition.
The pile of guts was a black blob of flies that buzzed like a saw. After a
while, these flies found Simon. Gorgged, they elided by his renels of sweat and
drank. They tickled under his nostrils and played leapfrog on his thighs. They
were black and iridescent green and without number. And in front of Simon,
the lord of the flies hung on his stick and grinned. At last Simon gave up and
looked back, saw the white teeth and dim eyes, the blood, and his gaze was hailed
by that ancient, inescapable recognition. In Simon's right temple, a pulse began to beat on the
brain. Ralph and Piggy lay in the sand, gazing at the fire and idly flicking
pebbles into its smokeless heat. "That branch is gone. Where's Sam
and Eric? We ought to get some more wood. We're out of green branches."
Ralph sighed and stood up. There were no shadows under the palms on the
platform. Only this strange light that seemed to come from everywhere at once,
high up among the bulging clouds, thunder went off like a gun. "We're
going to get buckets of rain. What about the fire? Ralph trotted into the forest
and returned with a wide spray of green which he dumped on the fire. The branch
crackled, the leaves curled, and the yellow smoke expanded. Piggy made an
aimless little pattern in the sand with his fingers. Trouble is, we haven't got
enough people for a fire. You got to treat Sam and Eric as one turn. They do
everything together, of course. Well, that isn't fair. Don't you see? They
ought to do two turns. Ralph considered this and understood. He was vexed to
find how little he thought like a grown-up and sighed again. The island
was getting worse and worse. Piggy looked at the fire. You'll want another
green branch soon. Ralph rolled over.
Piggy, what are we going to do? Just have to get on without him. But the
fire. He frowned at the black and white mess in which lay the unburnt ends of
branches. He tried to formulate. I'm scared. He saw Piggy look up and
blundered on. Not of the beast. I mean, I'm scared of that, too. But nobody else
understands about the fire. If someone threw you a rope when you were drowning.
If a doctor said, "Take this because if you don't take it, you'll die." You
would, wouldn't you? I mean, of course I would. Can't they see? Can't they
understand? Without the smoke signal, we'll die here. Look at that. A wave of
heated air trembled above the ashes, but without a trace of smoke. We can't keep
one fire going, and they don't care. And what's more? He looked intensely into
Piggy's streaming face. What's more, I don't sometimes. Supposing I got like
the others, not caring. What have become of us? Piggy took off his glasses, deeply
troubled. I don't know, Ralph. We just got to go on, that's all. That's what
grown-ups would do. Ralph, having begun the business of unburdening himself,
continued, "Piggy, what's wrong?" Piggy looked at him in astonishment. "Do you
mean that? No, not it. I mean, what makes things break up like they do?"
Piggy rubbed his glasses slowly and thought. When he understood how far
Ralph had gone toward accepting him, he flushed pinkly with pride. "I don't
know, Ralph. I expect it's him."
"Jack. Jack." A taboo was evolving around that word, too. Ralph nodded
solemnly. "Yes," he said. "I suppose it must be." The forest near them burst
into uproar. Demonic figures with faces of white and red and green rushed out,
howling so that the littles fled, screaming. Out of the corner of his
eyes, Ralph saw Piggy running. Two figures rushed at the fire, and he
prepared to defend himself, but they grabbed half-burnt branches and raced
away along the beach. The three others stood still, watching Ralph, and he saw
that the tallest of them, stark naked, save for the paint and a belt, was Jack.
Ralph had his breath back, and spoke, "Well." Jack ignored him, lifted his
spear, and began to shout, "Listen all of you. Me and my hunters, we're living
along the beach by a flat rock. We hunt and feast and have fun. If you want to
join my tribe, come and see us. Perhaps I'll let you join. Perhaps not." He
paused and looked round. He was safe from shame or self-consciousness behind
the mask of his paint, and could look at each of them in turn. Ralph was kneeling
by the remains of the fire like a sprinter at his mark, and his face was
half hidden by hair and smut. Sam and Eric peered together around a palm tree
at the edge of the forest. a little and howled creased and crimson by the
bathing pool and Piggy stood on the platform the white cotch gripped in his
hands. Tonight we're having a feast.
We've killed a pig and we've got meat.
You can come and eat with us if you like. Up in the cloud canyons the
thunder boomed again. Jack and the two anonymous savages with him swayed,
looking up and then recovered. The little went on howling. Jack was waiting
for something. He whispered urgently to the others. Go on now. The two savages
murmured. Jack spoke sharply. Go on. The two savages looked at each other, raised
their spears together, and spoke in time. The chief has spoken. Then the
three of them turned and trotted away.
Presently, Ralph rose to his feet, looking at the place where the savages
had vanished. Sam and Eric came, talking in an odd whisper. I thought it was, and
I was scared, Piggy stood above them on the platform, still holding the conch.
That was Jack and Maurice and Robert, said Ralph. Aren't they having fun? I
thought I was going to have asthma.
Sucks to your asthma. When I saw Jack, I was sure he'd go for the conch. can't
think why. The group of boys looked at the white shell with affectionate
respect. Piggy placed it in Ralph's hand, and the little onins, seeing the
familiar symbol, started to come back.
Not here. He turned toward the platform, feeling the need for ritual. First went
Ralph, the white created, then Piggy, very grave. Then the twins, then the littles and the
others. Sit down, all of you. They raided us for fire. They're having fun.
But the Ralph was puzzled by the shudder that flickered in his brain. There was
something he wanted to say. Then the shutter had come down. But the They were
regarding him gravely, not yet troubled by any doubts about his sufficiency.
Ralph pushed the idiot hair out of his eyes and looked at Piggy. But the Oh,
the fire. Of course, the fire. He started to laugh, then stopped and
became fluent instead. The fire is the most important thing. Without the fire, we can't be
rescued. I'd like to put on war paint and be a savage, but we must keep the
fire burning. The fire is the most important thing on the island. Because
because he paused again, and the silence became full of doubt and wonder. Piggy
whispered urgently, "Rescue! Oh yes, without the fire, we can't be rescued.
So we must stay by the fire and make smoke." When he stopped, no one said
anything. After the many brilliant speeches that have been made on this
very spot, Ralph's remarks seemed lame, even to the little. At last, Bill held
out his hands for the cunchch. "Now we can't have the fire up there, because we
can't have the fire up there. We need more people to keep it going. Let's go
to this feast and tell them the fire is hard on the rest of us." and the hunting
and all that being savages. I mean, it must be jolly good fun. Sam and Eric
took the cunch. That must be fun, like Bill says. And as he's invited us to a
feast, meat crackling. I could do with some meat, Ralph held up his hand. Why
shouldn't we get our own meat? The twins looked at each other. Bill answered. We
don't want to go in the jungle. Ralph grimaced. He, you know, goes. He's a
hunter. They're all hunters. That's different. No one spoke for a moment.
Then Piggy muttered to the sand. Meat.
The little sat solemnly thinking of meat and dribbling. Overhead the cannon
boomed again and the dry palm frrons clattered in a sudden gust of hot
wind. "You are silly little boy," said the lord of the flies. "Just an
ignorant, silly little boy," Simon moved his swollen tongue, but said nothing.
"Don't you agree?" said the Lord of the Flies. "Aren't you just a silly little
boy?" Simon answered him in the same silent voice. "Well then," said the Lord of the
Flies, "you'd better run off and play with the others. They think you're
baddy. You don't want Ralph to think you're baddy, do you? You like Ralph a
lot, don't you? And Piggy and Jack.
Simon's head was tilted slightly up. His eyes could not break away, and the Lord
of the Flies hung in space before him.
What are you doing out here all alone?
Aren't you afraid of me? Simon shook.
There isn't anyone to help you. Only me, and I'm the beast. Simon's mouth
labored, brought forth audible words.
Pig's head on a stick. Fancy thinking the beast was something you could hunt
and kill, said the head. For a moment or two, the forest and all the other dimly
appreciated places echoed with the parody of laughter. You knew, didn't
you? I'm part of you. Close, close, close. I'm the reason why it's no go,
why things are what they are. The laughter shivered again. Come now, said
the Lord of the Flies. Get back to the others, and we'll forget the whole
thing. Simons head wobbled. His eyes were half closed, as though he were
imitating the obscene thing on the stick. He knew that one of his times was
coming on. The Lord of the Flies was expanding like a balloon. This is
ridiculous. You know perfectly well you'll only meet me down there. So don't
try to escape. Simon's body was arched and stiff. The lord of the flies spoke
in the voice of a schoolmaster. This has gone quite far enough. My poor misguided
child. Do you think you know better than I do? There was a pause. I'm warning
you. I'm going to get angry. Do you see?
You're not wanted. Understand? We are going to have fun on this island.
Understand? We are going to have fun on this island. So don't try it on, my poor
misguided boy. Or else, Simon found, he was looking into a vast mouth. There was
blackness within, a blackness that spread. Or else, said the Lord of the
Flies, we shall do. You see, Jack and Roger and Maurice and Robert and Bill and Piggy
and Ralph, do you see? Simon was inside the mouth. He fell down and lost
consciousness. Lord of the